NISCHAY NEGI

San Francisco Bay Area nischay.negi@gmail.com | (415) 297-3023 www.linkedin.com/in/nischay-negi

SUMMARY

I graduated from the University of California, Irvine with a Bachelor's in Computer Science and Engineering and have 1 year of experience working with experienced teams on building tools and services with languages like **Ruby**, **C+**, and **Python**. I have experience working with **TDD**, modern build pipelines and **MVC** architecture e.g. Ruby on Rails along with hands-on experience in **SQL** and **AWS** (EC2/RDS).

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Intern | Tapjoy Inc | San Francisco, California

Core Engineering Team

July 2018 - Sept 2018

- Developed modules that fetched metadata for serving Vast Ads to the game developer.
- Responsible for Test Driven Development to ensure the end to end functionality. Wrote over 20 separate testing suites.
- Participated in an Agile workflow (Daily Standups, Sprints, Retrospectives, etc).
- Participated in the API client design for building Tapjoy's Vast Template.

BizOps Team

June 2017 - Sept 2017

- Built database and workflow tools for the business operations team.
- Used Ruby and MySQL to create a bulk upload tool, removing the need to manually update about 150 records a day.
- Worked with operations to reduce the friction on a common data modification task, by creating a custom view with HAML and Javascript.
- Handled database schema migration and ETL process for the employee database, ensuring it reflected the management hierarchy.

PROJECTS

ThirdEye | Gesture Controlled Drone | Demo

Sept 2018 - March 2019

OpenCV, Python, CoDrone

- Senior Design Project that used an open-source computer vision algorithm with gesture recognition to control a drone in a hands-free setting.
- Built safety features and a keyboard controller for when the drone can not detect gestures.

Wumpus World | Game Al

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

Python

- Designed a smart AI robot navigation game to avoid blocks and pits to achieve its goals.
- Applied search algorithms e.g. DFS, A* to achieve a score of one standard deviation above the mean.

RISC-V Processor | Single/Multi-Cycle Processor

SvstemVeriloa

Jan 2018 - March 2018

- Quarter long coursework for designing and programming a Single Cycle Processor to implement basic instructions.
- Built a Multi-Cycle Processor based on the Single Cycle Processor using pipelining methods.

Othello | Strategy Board Game

C++, Python

April 2016 - June 2016

- Designed Othello board game Artificial Intelligence and GUI for intraclass competition. Al was within the top 50 out of three-hundred students.
- Applied efficient data structures and search algorithms to improve the performance of the AI, including DFS and k-ary trees.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine, CA

Sept 2015 - June 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering | Henry Samueli School Of Engineering GPA 3.4 Selected Coursework: Object-Oriented Design, Embedded Software, Data Structures & Algorithms, Operating Systems, Digital Signal Processing, Network Analysis, Compilers

SKILLS

Languages: C++, Ruby, Java, Python, Ruby on Rails, HTML, System Verilog Technologies/Environment: Mac OS, Windows, Linux, MySQL, MATLAB, Vim